JIHYE CHOI

San Jose, CA | 714-290-2032 | jihye1023@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jihyechoi1023/ | github.com/jhye1023 | jhye1023.github.io/JihyeChoi/

SUMMARY

Data analyst with a certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley Extension and 6+ years of experience in the financial industry. Experienced in reporting with data to facilitate executive-level decision making. Maintaining priorities on strict deadlines and a fast learner who can absorb new ideas and skills. Finds great satisfaction in extracting insights from data that inform decision-making and drive growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Flask, Matplotlib, API, JavaScript, JSON, HTML, CSS, D3, SQL, SQLAlchemy, MongoDB, Tableau, Microsoft Office

PROJECTS

Language Demographic in the US | https://github.com/tomrecht/Project-1

- Worked in a team of four to explore recent trends in the population of speakers of foreign languages in the US, both nationally and at the regional level.
- Tools used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib, Gmaps and Numpy.

New York Properties Sale | https://github.com/fsabree/final_project | https://nyc-home-sale.herokuapp.com/

- Worked in a team of three to analyze and visualize the data of the sold properties in New York City during a certain time period.
- Tools used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Tableau, Plotly, AWS and Skit-learn.

EXPERIENCE

AVP & Accounting Officer Open Bank

July 2015 - February 2020

Los Angeles, CA

- Presented financial information in a clear and concise manner to management.
- Performed monthly income forecasts against annual targets.
- Simplified complex excel-based financial worksheets and reduced time to create financial reports by 50%.
- Analyzed current and past trends in key performance indicators including net interest margin, return on equity, return on assets, efficiency ratio, and book value per share.
- Updated and implemented new procedures to enhance the workflow of the accounting department.

Accounting Supervisor US Metro Bank

September 2013 - June 2015

Garden Grove, CA

- Assisted in various accounting activities, including account payable, journal entry, bank account reconciliation and auditing.
- Supported monthly financial closing by collecting documents and ensuring all financial deadlines were met.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley
Analytics and Visualization Certificate
General Assembly
SQL Bootcamp
University of California, San Diego
Bachelor of Arts in Economics, minor in Accounting

Berkeley, CA February 2020 - August 2020 Santa Monica, CA October 2019 San Diego, CA